在想动作呢
Visualizing?
好了  该你上场了  小猛虎
All right. You're up, tiger.
感觉怎么样  你脸色不太好
You feel all right? You look a little pale.
-我很好  -脖子还疼吗
- I'm fine. - Does your neck still hurt?
过会就没事了
It'll be fine.
要不然你还是做转体两周半吧
Maybe you should do the two-and-a-half instead.
我要做转体三周
I'm gonna do the three.
完成两周半总比...
Well,it's better to nail the two-and-a-half than--
我会完成三周的
I'm gonna nail the three.
好吧
All right.
那我们就给那些老骨头们展示展示
Well, let's show these senior citizens
一个训练有素的十二岁孩子的本领
what a well-coached 12-year-old can do, huh?
下一位选手  两次国家青少年组冠军
Next diver, two-time National Junior Champion,
玛丽·卡洛尔
Mary Carroll.
可恶
Damn it.
你能行的  加油  只要
You can do this. Come on, just...
镇定  镇定
see it. See it.
腾空高  屈体  压水花
Big jump. Pike out. Rip it.
快打911  叫救护车
Call 911. We need an ambulance.
-我看见灯亮着  -现在是白天
- I saw the light on. - It's daytime.
我这是委婉的说法
It's a figure of speech.
你总是这么望文生义
Always so literal.
-新拐杖嘛  -是啊
- Got a new cane. - Yeah.
店里的伙计说这个是轻质的
Guy in the store said it was slimming.
直线条纹
Vertical stripe.
你来干吗
Why are you here?
沃格勒完蛋了
Vogler is dead.
什么  发生什么了
What? What happened?
我这还是在用修辞手法
Again with the literal translation.
沃格勒  他的象征意义
Vogler, the idea.
破坏专家  守财奴  "向我俯首称臣"先生
Mr. Destructo, Mr. Moneybags. "Bow down before me".
他离开医院了
He is gone from the hospital.
所以一切都可以回到从前了
So things can go back to the way they were.
以前有点怪怪的
The way they were was kind of weird.
我喜欢怪怪的
Hmm. Weird works for me.
你究竟什么意思  直接说
What are you saying? Literally.
-我希望你回来  -为什么
- I want you to come back. - Why?
麻烦你放轻松
Please unclench.
你不在当班  你一做那动作
You're not on the clock, and when you do that,
我就紧张  整个就这么回事
I clench and it's a whole thing.
你看一下呼你什么事吧
Could you look at your pager?
不是什么大事
It's no big deal.
有个传染病  不是我的专长
Some sort of epidemic. Not my area.
你应该去处理  这是要紧事
You should go. It's important.
我现在做的才是要紧事
What I'm doing now is important.
为什么要我回去
Why do you want me back?
因为你是个好医生
'Cause you're a good doctor.
-就这样吗  -这样不够吗
- That's it? - That's not enough?
对我来说不够
Not for me.
治你的传染病去吧
Go deal with your plague.
[这里是隔离区]
You are in a quarantined area.
[请保持冷静  排队等候]
Please remain calm and stay in line.
[马上会有医生为您诊治]
A doctor will see you shortly.
[医生为您检查时]
When you see a doctor,
[会给您一份表格  有蓝色和黄色之分]
you will receive a blue or yellow form.
[拿到蓝色表格的就诊者]
Patients with blue forms
[请立即撤离至停车场]
must immediately exit to the parking lot.
豪斯医生  这里需要你
Dr. House. Need you here.
抱歉了  这么多病人
Sorry. Lot of sick people.
我可能会染上什么毛病
I might catch something.
有个裁判在校园游泳中心昏倒了
A judge at the campus pool center collapsed.
腰椎穿刺显示他得了高传染性的细菌性脑膜炎
L.P. revealed a virulent form of bacterial meningitis.
真棒  你已经做出了诊断  用不着我了
Great. You got it diagnosed. You don't need me.
游泳中心内有两千五百人暴露在感染环境中
2,500 people at the pool center were exposed.
现在正被送往附近的所有医院
They're being bused to all the neighboring hospitals.
这是资源问题  不是诊断问题
That's a problem with resources, not diagnostics.
我会全然不知所措  不停的帮倒忙
I-- I'd be completely lost, get in everyone's way.
乔  豪斯医生没有蓝色纸条
Joe. Dr. House doesn't have a blue slip.
没拿到蓝色纸条者不得离开隔离区
No one leaves the quarantine area without a blue slip.
你是这家医院的医生
You are a doctor at this hospital.
拿点医生的样子出来
Act like one.
还有...
And...
吃了这些
take these.
102度
102.
你赢得一次二楼之旅
You win a trip to the second floor.
下一个
Next.
好的  没有发热  没有皮疹
All right. No fever. No rash.
你没事  服下这两粒药
You're fine. Take these two pills.
出门时向警卫出示这张蓝色纸条
And show this blue slip to Security on your way out.
下一位
Next.
吃下这些药  回家去
Take these. Go home.
-跟你女儿谈谈心  -什么
- Talk to your daughter. - What?
你的裤子  你的衬衫
Your pants, your blouse,
你的围巾都是刚刚干洗过的
your scarf are all freshly dry cleaned.
除了你的夹克
Everything except your jacket.
上面有个污渍  大概两天前粘上去的
It's got a smudge on it. Probably two days old.
这说明你不知道你的夹克被人穿过
Which means you didn't know the jacket had been worn.
所以说  要么你的丈夫是个异装癖
So either your husband is a cross-dresser,
要么你的女儿曾背着你穿过这件衣服
or your daughter's been borrowing your clothes without telling you.
她可能想打扮得成熟点  混进酒吧
She probably wants to look older to get into bars.
我没有女儿
I don't have a daughter.
下一个
Next.
我被传染了吗
So I have it?
拿这张黄色表格去二楼
Take the yellow form to the second floor.
-你会没事的  -我会死的
- You're gonna be fine. - I'm gonna die.
这是可以治疗的  你只要去二楼就行了
It's treatable-- as long as you go to the second floor.
下一个
Next.
发热吗  是不是表示我被传染了
Fever? Does that mean I have it?
身上出疹子吗
Do you have a rash?
衣服拉上来
Come on.
这是我的新泳衣弄出来的  已经一个星期了
It's from my new bathing suit. I've had it a week.
哦
Yeah.
脖子疼吗  疼的话你就中大奖了
Does your neck hurt? If it does, you hit the trifecta.
那没什么
It's nothing.
我为了做好转体三周半抱膝跳拉伤的
I pulled it trying to do a three-and-a-half tuck.
-你父母在哪儿  -我家在芝加哥
- Where are your parents? - We live in Chicago.
我和教练一起来的
I'm here with my coach.
我想看看你在写什么
I wanted to see what you were writing.
像这样做
Go like this.
再这样
吃了这些药
Take these pills.
拿着蓝色纸条你就可以走了
Blue slip will get you out of here.
下一位
Next.
你跟我来
You're coming with me.
[请前往二楼做进一步检查]
Proceed to the second floor for further examination.
你需要去二楼做个CT扫描
You're gonna need a C.T. Scan. Second floor.
坐电梯上去  跟着队伍走
Take the elevators, follow the parade.
下一个
Next.
也许是系统性疾病
Maybe it's something systemic.
或者是脑膜炎
Or maybe it's meningitis.
她的疹子一周前就有了
She's had the rash a week.
如果是脑膜炎  早没命了
If it was this meningitis she'd be dead by now.
你们几个以为楼下的活儿都干完了
You guys figure we're done down there?
难道那八百号人里三层外三层的
The 800 people milling around
在排队等上厕所吗
are just waiting for the bathroom?
十二岁的女性
Twelve-year-old female.
发热  皮疹  脖子疼  却不是脑膜炎
Fever, rash, neck pains. Not meningitis.
脑膜炎明明就是这么定义的
It's the definition of meningitis.
没错  椎管里有脓液
Sure. Pus in the spinal canal
头上下活动  会使你的脖子疼
makes it hurt to move your head up and down,
但她的脖子只有左右转动时才疼
but her neck only hurts moving side to side.
-噢  左右呀  -这不符合脑膜炎的症状
- Oh, side to side. - Doesn't fit.
你们三人  马上去门诊大厅
The three of you, lobby, now.
你们忙着分发的那些药
Those little pills you're passing out so efficiently...
对洛加尼斯小姐根本没用
aren't gonna do Miss Louganis squat.
你是存心不想去处理疫情
You just don't want to deal with the epidemic.
照你这么说
That's right.
我安排一个十二岁的孩子进行一系列危险
I'm subjecting a 12-year-old to a battery of dangerous
的有创检查纯粹是为了摆脱无聊喽
and invasive tests to avoid being bored.
好吧 也许我是做得出来  但现在不是
Okay, maybe I would do that. But I'm not.
假如被你说对了
If it turns out she's got meningitis,
她确实是脑膜炎  我心悦诚服
you're right, you win;
但如果我们现在回楼下去  结果她死了
but if we go back downstairs and she dies--
你的脸会红得像猴屁股
your face will be so red.
给你一小时
You have one hour.
做一个脊椎穿刺
Get a lumbar puncture.
有些脑部感染病症很会玩躲猫猫
Some brain infections can be pretty clever at hide-and-seek.
我来给她做血液化验
I'll get on her blood work.
不  不用你去
No, you won't.
先生  你
You, sir,
要去查找宇宙之中所有可能导致脖子疼的原因
will research all the causes in the universe of neck pain.
列出来单子可是会有两里长的
The list is, like, two miles long.
从字母A开始
Start with the letter "A".
给她用利福平
And put her on rifampin.
利福平是治脑膜炎的  你刚刚还在说...
Rifampin is for meningitis. You just said--
万一我错了
In case I'm wrong.
曾经发生过
It has happened.
布兰达
Brenda,
2046房间需要做全血球计数
I need a C.B.C.
和生化7项检查
Chem 7 in 2046.
-等着  -抱歉  借过
- Hold on. - Excuse me. Excuse me.
-这儿排着队呢  -所以我才说抱歉的
- Hey, there's a line here. - That's why I said excuse me.
布兰达  我需要一个床位和...
Brenda, I need a bed and a
我们都需要东西
We all need stuff.
再推我试试看
Push me again.
布兰达  我需要一张床位和一个护士
Brenda, I need a bed and a nurse
我要做脊椎穿刺
for a lumbar puncture.
至少四小时内都没有空余的床和护士
No beds, no nurses for at least four hours.
我只有一个小时
I've only got one.
你的病人一个小时之内
Your patient only has an hour
不做脊椎穿刺就活不成吗
to live unless she gets a lumbar puncture?
卡迪只给我们一小时找出这个病人的病因
Cuddy only gave us an hour to work on the patient.
到后面排队去
Back of the line.
[在没有看过医生前]
Do not leave the quarantine area
[请不要擅自离开隔离区]
until you have been seen by a doctor.
[医生为您检查后]
When you see a doctor,
[会给您一份表格  有蓝色和黄色之分...]
you will receive a blue or yellow form--
奴佛卡因[局部麻醉剂]会麻痹你
This novocaine will numb you
减轻你的痛苦
for the lumbar puncture.
抱歉得在这种人来人往的地方给你做穿刺
Sorry this has to be so public, Mary.
平时比赛的时候都穿着泳装
Normally I'm in a bathing suit
有五千双眼睛盯着我的屁股呢
with 5,000 people staring at my butt.
我早就习惯了
I can block this out.
这些孩子都很成熟
These kids are all very mature.
全国各地到处跑  参加一场又一场的赛事
Travel around the country from event to event.
好了  抱住膝盖  把头蜷进去
Okay, I want you to hold your knees and tuck your head.
-就像跳水那样  -没错
- Like a dive? - Exactly.
好的  非常棒  不用屏气
Good. Great. Don't forget to breathe.
好的
All right.
对不起
Sorry.
真是的  教练  帮帮忙呀
Geez. Coach, help me out here.
帮我挡着点  不然我就要扎错地方了
Play a little defense before I poke the wrong thing.
好了  这就开始了
Okay, here we go.
我感觉到了  我感觉到了
Ow. I feel it. Ow. I feel it.I fee
放松点  玛丽  放松点
Try to relax, Mary. Try to relax.
放松
Relax.
-看到哪个字母了  -A
- What letter are you up to? - "A".
查阅那么多东西很折磨人吧
Torture combing through all that stuff, ain't it?
-相当枯燥  烦死人了  -没什么
- Real dull. Awful. - It's no problem.
那真是谢天谢地
Well, thank goodness.
好多人都讨厌做这种事
A lot of people would resent having to do this.
[如果您拿到的是蓝色表格  请立刻离开]
If you receive a blue form, please exit the area.
[如果拿到黄色表格]
If you receive a yellow form,
[请到二楼]
please proceed to the second floor.
刚才在这儿的那个十二岁小姑娘哪儿去了
Where's the 12-year-old girl that was here?
要用推床
Needed the gurney.
她刚做过脊椎穿刺
She just had a lumbar puncture.
-不可以移动的  -对不起
-She's not supposed to be moved.- Sorry.
我们要用推床
We needed the gurney.
还好吗  头部有什么不适吗
You okay? How's your head feeling?
她说她头疼  头晕
She's got a headache and she's dizzy.
穿刺后不应该让她移动的
She shouldn't have been moved after the procedure.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我没事  检测结果怎么样了
I'm fine. What did the test show?
不是脑膜炎  也没有其它感染
No meningitis and no other infections.
可是你没带蓝色表格过来
But you're not carrying a blue form.
我还有别的病  对吗
I have something else, don't I?
你的这些症状是有原因的
Something's causing your symptoms.
今晚你要留院观察
We're gonna keep you here overnight.
我知道现在这里有点混乱
I know it's a little crazy in here,
不过相信很快会恢复正常的
but hopefully it'll settle down...
到时我们就可以给你安排病房了
and we'll be able to get you a room.
对不起
I'm sorry.
平常我不是这么情绪化的  我只是...
I'm not usually all emotional like this. I just--
你很勇敢  你父母的飞机很快就到了
You're doing great. Your folks land in a few hours.
我只是...  我没有睡觉  感觉好累
I just-- I haven't slept. I'm so tired.
天哪  我的眼睛在流血
Oh, my God. My eye's bleeding.
这是什么  怎么回事
What is it? What's happening?
哦  别担心
Oh, don't worry.
我们生怕你有脑膜炎  给你用的的抗生素
The antibiotic we gave you in case you had meningitis
会使你的眼泪变红
can turn your tears reddish.
那不是血
That's not blood.
但是这个
But that--
这个是血
That's blood.
你要把这个伸进我肚子里吗
That's going into my stomach?
洗胃结果表明你的消化道出血
The lavage showed blood in your G.I. Tract.
我们要找到出血位置
We need to find where it's coming from.
这没什么感觉的
You won't feel it.
我会给你的喉咙里喷点儿麻药
I'm gonna numb the back of your throat,
福曼医生会给你打针镇静剂
and Dr. Foreman is gonna give you a sedative.
张开嘴
Open.
咽下去
Swallow.
侧过身来
Now lay on your side for me.
好了  开始
And... here we go.
想想办法
Yell fire or something.
各位  这里是高度感染区域
People, this area is highly contagious.
请退后  不要站在高度感染区内
Please step back. Highly contagious.
可以了  尽量放松  玛丽
All right. Try to relax, Mary.
一会儿就好
This shouldn't take too long.
我看不出任何伤口或者病灶
I don't see any tears or lesions.
行了
All right.
可以看到胃部了
I'm in the stomach.
没有出血
It's not bleeding.
她口腔里有超过一汤勺的血
There was more than a tablespoon of blood in the mouth
所以一定有出血的地方
so it's gotta be there.
会不会是小肠
Maybe her small intestine.
消化道有30尺
Thirty feet of digestive tract,
哪里都有可能
it could be anywhere in there.
我们用这个是看不到的
We're not gonna see it with this.
信不信由你
Believe it or not,
这是个照相机
this is a camera.
你把它吞了
You swallow it,
它会穿过你的整个消化系统
and it goes all the way through your system.
天线接收到这个胶囊发出的信号
The antennae pick up the signal from the pill.
然后我们可以看到你小肠的画面
Then we look at the video of your intestines,
找到出血点  把它补好
see where the blood is coming from, and fix it.
好吗  需要水吗
All right? Water?
喝下去吧
Down the hatch.
我好像看过这部电影
Think I've seen this movie.
结局有点黑暗
The ending's kind of dark.
来一个吗
You want one?
为什么是你做内窥镜
How come you did the endoscopy?
-他找我帮忙  -她的血压太高了
- He asked for help. - Her blood pressure was high.
福曼不是你的老板
Foreman is not your boss.
我叫你做事的时候...
When I tell you to do something--
喔  等会儿
Whoa. Hold it there.
倒退几帧
Back it up a couple of frames.
看点来了
Oh, yeah. That's your money shot.
-我没有看到任何东西  -没有吗
- I don't see anything. - Really?
她小肠右侧那个"巨大"的东西
"Ginormous" thing on the right side of her intestine.
没有吸引到你吗
That doesn't intrigue you?
你所谓"巨大"是非常大
Does "Ginormous" mean really big,
还是非常非常小
or really, really small?
-我是看不出什么东西来  -是那儿吗
- 'Cause I don't see anything. - There?
是Dieulafoy病吗
The Dieulafoy?
是的话  我们可以给那些血管消消肿
Well, we can burn off the swollen blood vessel,
可这不能解释她的其它症状
but it still doesn't account for her other symptoms.
是不能  但它说明了一些问题
No, but it does tell us something.
只是我还不知道是什么
Though I have no idea what.
可能是肠套叠的前兆
Could be a precursor to intestinal intussusception.
前兆不会导致其它任何症状  还会是什么
Precursor isn't causing all her other symptoms. What else?
你  马上去大厅
You, in the lobby now.
我腿疼  我也有蓝色小纸条
I hurt my leg. I have a note.
一个小时已过  算起来是三个小时了
You had your hour-- three, actually.
奇斯医生  我和你说过
Dr. Chase, I told you to
时间到了提醒我们
tell us when our time was up.
-她肠内出血  -她可以等等
- She has intestinal bleeding. - She'll wait.
又拉来两车人  楼下需要你帮忙
Two more buses just arrived. We need you downstairs.
错  你需要的是更多的护士
No, you need more nurses,
但你裁减了护士的人手
but you cut back on the nursing staff,
所以现在你叫医生干护士的活
so now you've got doctors doing what nurses should be doing.
这我承认
That's true.
不过我在想这是不是
I wonder if that has anything to do
你导致我们损失一亿美金的呢
with you costing us $100 million.
[请注意  如果您没有蓝色的表格]
Attention. If you do not have a blue form,
[请不要离开隔离区域]
you will not be allowed to leave the quarantine area.
走吧  你自由了
Go. Be free.
如果不是肠套叠
If it's not the intussusception,
会不会是胃癌
what about stomach cancer?
-她腹痛吗  -没有
- Does she have any abdominal pain? - No.
那就不是胃癌  查过败血症没
Then it's not stomach cancer. Have you ruled out sepsis?
脊椎穿刺和血涂片结果显示无感染
The L.P. and blood smears showed no signs of infection.
拿着  吃了这两片药就可以走了
Here. Take these two pills and you can go.
化验室现在是超负荷工作
Well, the lab's working at double their capacity.
可能会有人忙中出错
Maybe someone screwed up.
不发热  无脖子疼
No fever, no neck pain.
乘电梯到三楼
Take the elevator to the third floor--
喂  喂  喂  不是那个表格
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wrong form.
没有发热  脖子也不痛  她没事
No fever, no neck pain. She's fine.
她的头发没有氯的味道
Smell her hair. No chlorine.
说明她不是从泳池那边过来的
Which means she wasn't at the pool,
就是说她主动闯进隔离区域的
which means she's come to a quarantined area...
因此她要么是傻子要么是疯子
because she's an idiot or she's insane.
你说谁会这么笨啊
No one is that stupid.
精神病区在东楼  拜拜
East wing, psych ward. Bye-bye.
骨癌会导致脖子疼
Neck pain could be a symptom for bone cancer.
已经查到B开头的了啊  干得好
You up to the B's? Well done.
这可以解释她为何有脑膜炎的症状
That would account for all her meningeal symptoms--
皮疹  发热  你没事
rash, fever. You're fine.
服下这两片药
Take these two pills.
去取她的骨髓样本
Get a sample of her bone marrow.
-就在这儿吗  -利用休息时间
- From here? - Break time.
我要的时间可不止十五分钟
I need more than 15 minutes.
把奇斯的也用上
Use Chase's break too.
去吧
Go.
你干脆炒了奇斯得了
You should just fire Chase.
什么  那多没乐趣啊
What, and miss out on all this fun?
那你打算先折磨他一阵子再开除他
So you're gonna torture him for a while and then fire him?
你还真无情
That's cold.
你不觉得他活该吗
You don't think he has it coming?
-我说了开了他  -你这才无情呢
- Hey, I said fire him. - That's cold.
-他只是想保住自己的饭碗  -开玩笑
- All he did was save his job. - What?
他明显搅得你不得安宁
He completely screwed you over.
右转
Right rudder.
侧倾  侧倾  侧倾
Bank, bank, bank.
咖啡好喝吗
Good coffee?
整个医院都忙得团团转
The rest of this hospital is busting its tail
而你却在...
and you're--
-你在干嘛  -使劲想
- What are you doing? - Trying to think
全食食品公司生产部门以外的任何东西
of anything except the produce department at Whole Foods.
我在工作  有点热
I am working. It got hot.
不要像个十三岁孩子一样幼稚
Stop acting like a 13-year-old.
不好意思  只是通常在医院院长身上
Sorry. You just don't usually see breasts
看不到如此美妙的胸部
like that on deans of medicine.
女人就不能当院长  还是只有丑女才行
Oh, women can't be heads of hospitals? Or just ugly ones?
不是  她们可以是美女
No, they can be babes.
只是一般看不到她们的某个部位
It's just you don't usually see their fun bags.
约好三点来应聘卡梅隆医生职位的人
Your 3 o'clock interview
已经在你办公室了
for Dr. Cameron's position is in your office.
今天面试不成了  不知道你听说了没
Not interviewing today. I don't know if you've heard,
现在医院里传染病肆虐
but there's this big-time epidemic.
好多人病了  吐在过道里  一塌糊涂
Many sick people puking in the hallways, it's crazy.
我会叫应聘的人先回去  我们可以重新安排
I'll send the interviewee home, we can reschedule.
不  你不要去  你得面试这个人
No, you won't. You will interview this person.
只要他能说全两个句子
And if he can put two sentences together,
就派他去大厅
you will send him to the lobby...
他会在那里好好工作
where he will do his job.
不像你们两个
Unlike the two of you.
别这样
Come on.
你知道我没办法在过道做骨髓抽样
You know I can't do a bone marrow aspiration in the hallway.
我也没办法给你一个治疗室
And I can't give you a procedure room.
我不过要一个接近无菌的环境
I just need something at least close to a sterile environment.
我也就是想再要10个护士
I need ten more nurses.
布兰达  听着  听着  她会死的
Brenda, listen. Listen. She'll die.
到那时她就有张床了  放到那边去
At least she'll have a bed then. Put that over there.
那些柜子里是不是都是死人
Are there dead people in those cabinets?
我倒希望有人在
I hope that's who's in there.
别紧张  放松
Just be calm. Relax.
坚持住
Hang on.
你知道吗
You know,
我非常欣赏你那种我行我素
I really admire the way you don't care what anyone thinks.
坚持己见  随心所欲的那种风格
You just do what you want, the way you want.
你是在霍普金斯读的本科和医学院吗
So you went to Hopkins for both undergrad and med school?
-是的  -他参加乐队呢
- That's right. - He's in a band.
-你喜欢音乐  -十分着迷
- You're into music? - Totally.
你演奏哪种音乐
What kind of music do you play?
大多时候是蓝调
Mostly blues, you know,
詹姆斯·科顿  一些原创作品之类的
James Cotton, some original stuff.
哦  伙计  这职位非你莫属了
Oh, dude, you are so hired.
真的吗
Really?
-门儿都没有  -为什么
- Not a chance. - Why?
纹身
Tattoo.
真没想到  你也会对
Wow. I thought you'd be the last person
叛逆的人有成见
to have a problem with nonconformity.
叛逆  是吧
Nonconformity. Right.
我都忘了上一次看见二十多岁的毛头小子
I can't remember the last time I saw a 20-something kid
手腕上纹有亚洲文字是什么时候的事了
with a tattoo of an Asian letter on his wrist.
你不过是一个顽劣的自由思想者
You are one wicked freethinker.
你想要叛逆吗  别耍酷
You want to be a rebel? Stop being cool.
像他那样随身带个笔套  再去剃个头
Wear a pocket protector like he does, and get a haircut,
剃成亚洲小孩儿那样
like the Asian kids who
他们在图书馆一坐就是二十个钟头
don't leave the library for 20-hour stretches.
他们才是我行我素的人
They're the ones who don't care what you think.
再见[日语]
Sayonara.
那我是不是应该把所有简历看一遍
So, should I go through all the resume
找有亚洲名字的
looking for Asian names?
实际上  那些亚洲孩子大概
Actually, the Asian kids are probably
只是迫于家长的压力
just responding to parental pressure,
不过我的观点依然成立
but my point is still valid.
医生说没说你几时能离开这里
So when do they think you're getting out of here?
他们也不知道
They don't know.
-你看起来没有生病  -但愿你没什么
- You don't look sick. - Better hope you're not.
这些设备看上去像是出土文物
This equipment looks like it's 100 years old.
刚从仓库拉出来的
Just got it out of storage.
虽然说是上一代的设备  但还是好用的
It is the previous generation, but it works just fine.
能不能请你们先...让我们单独聊会儿
Could you, uh-- Could you guys give us a second?
如果是好消息你可以告诉他们
If it's good news, you can tell them.
好吧  我们确定不是癌症
Okay. We're, uh, we're pretty sure it's not cancer.
-这是好事  -我会给你父母打电话
- Hey, that's great. - I'll call your parents.
不过  我们还不能让她走
Well, we still can't release her.
我们还没查明究竟是什么造成她的...
We still don't know yet exactly what's causing the--
玛丽
Mary?
她怎么了
What's wrong?
是失神发作  玛丽  你还好吗
She's having an absence seizure. Mary? You okay?
-她看上去没事  -快来人帮忙
- She looks fine. - I need some help over here.
马上注射两毫克安定
Push two milligrams Ativan, stat.
你确定是失神发作吗
Are you sure it was an absence seizure?
肯定是  她对周围的状况
Absolutely. She was totally unresponsive...
完全没有反应  也没有感知
and unaware of what was going on around her.
麻烦小声点儿  我们在工作
Do you mind? We're trying to work.
我们应该回大厅去
We should get back out there.
卡迪会来找我们的
Cuddy's gonna be looking for us.
找是找  但是找不着
Looking, but not finding.
有没有做脑电图呢
Did you do an E.E.G.?
发作的频率在增加
Seizure frequency's increasing.
现在基本上持续不断了
They-- They're almost constant now.
过去半小时内发作了五次
Five in the last half hour.
-说明  -肯定是她脑部有问题
- Which tells us - It's definitely in her brain.
-而且在恶化  -然后呢
- And it's getting worse. - And?
天哪  你是在便便还是生孩子
Good Lord. Are you having a bowl movement or a baby?
说不定是巴比妥类戒断反应
Could be barbiturate withdrawal
不  不可能是毒品
No, it can't be drugs.
她每场比赛都做药检
She's tested at every meet she competes at.
脑出血也会引起那些发作
A bleed in the brain could cause seizures.
老鼠药  也会导致脖子疼
Rat poison? Could also cause the neck pain.
你以为她是专啃她家车库地板的老鼠吗
You think she's eating off the floor of her folks' garage?
不一定是她自己
Doesn't have to be.
谁会对一个十二岁孩子下毒
Who would poison a 12-year-old?
我们来看看  有个十八岁的前冠军
Well, let's see now. There's the 18-year-old has-been
在全国比赛上被她打败了
that she beat out to make the Nationals,
前冠军的爹妈
the has-been's parents,
妒嫉的兄弟姐妹  疯狂的粉丝
jealous siblings, sociopathic swim fan,
还有就是大家常说的神经病
and then there's just your plain old garden variety whack job.
-知道什么是痔疮吗  -不知道
- You know what a hemorrhoid is? - No.
网上查查去
Well, Google it.
还有别吃甜甜圈  多吃点提子麦麸
And try some Raisin Bran instead of the donuts.
做个CT扫描  看看有没有颅内出血
Do a C.T. Scan. Check for intracranial bleeding.
门都没有  放射科已经爆满了
Not a chance. Radiology's totally swamped.
我们的病人若是颅内出血
If our patient's bleeding into her brain,
会在八小时之内死亡
she's gonna be dead in eight hours.
她是可能会死
She could be,
但如果脑膜炎病人不做CT就一定会死
but a meningitis patient will be without a C.T. Scan.
我在医学院的时候  有个教我的老教授
When I was in med school, I had this old professor
老是摸你的敏感部位吗
Who touched you in the naughty place?
在CT扫描技术诞生之前
Before the CT scan was introduced,
他是经颅超声方面的专家
he specialized in transcranial ultrasound.
是个古老的办法
Ancient,
但如果出血量大应该可以看出来
but if there's enough bleeding it might work.
你去  按照这个
Okay, do what the guy
不是神经学专家的家伙说的做
who didn't specialize in Neurology said.
这是我点子
It was my idea.
继续去查找从Q到Z开头的
You've still gotta cover "Q" To "Z".
不好意思  迟到了  我去上大号了
Sorry I'm late. I was taking a dump.
我猜想在这之后
I'm guessing I'm better off
跟你面试比较好
interviewing right after than right before.
派翠拉·吉尔马医生
Dr. Petra Gilmar,
格利高里·豪斯医生
Dr. Gregory House.
你是真会说四种语言
You actually speak four languages,
还是指望着
or are you just banking on
面试你的人统统不会
never being interviewed by anyone who does?
我确实会  而且还会用另外两种骂人
It's true, and I can swear in two more.
为什么不在黑泽尔医生那儿干了
Why are you leaving Dr. Hazel?
是不是爱上他  然后不知所措了
Did you fall for him and can't handle it,
还是反过来他爱上了你
or was it the other way around?
是啊  大多数的雇佣关系都是这样结束的吧
Yes, well, pretty much every fellowship ends that way.
不  不是那回事
No, it was nothing like that.
-你是犹太人吗  -是的
- You Jewish? - Yes.
传说中犹太人的前戏是真的吗
Is it true what they say about Jewish foreplay?
-你指哀求两小时  -我听说是四小时
- Two hours of begging? - I heard four.
这么说吧  其实我只是半个犹太人
Well, actually, I'm only half Jewish.
听着  我知道你喜欢和别人玩游戏
Look, I know you like to play games with people.
我也知道你喜欢说不堪入耳的话
I know you like to say outrageous things
然后观察别人的反应
and study how they react.
你要知道
What you should know about me
我是和四个哥哥一起长大
is that I grew up with four brothers.
只要你不动手动脚
Keep your hands to yourself,
我可以容忍你任何的言语
I'm okay with anything that comes out of your mouth.
好了  进行的不错
Uh, well, that's, uh, great.
我想你的情况我们都知道了
I think that's all we need.
-感谢你前来  -谢谢
- Thank you for coming by. -Thank you.
-就是她了  -不行
- That's our Hitler! - No way.
你开什么玩笑  她的背景完美
Are you kidding? Her background's perfect.
她聪明  显然也能忍受你的疯狂
She's smart, she can obviously deal with your insanity--
-你看到她的鞋子吗  -她的鞋子
- You see her shoes? - Her shoes?
怎么  VOGUE上的占星版
What, did your horoscope in Vogue
叫你要当心穿绿色鞋子的女人
tell you to avoid women wearing green shoes?
眼神笑容都可以伪装
The eyes can mislead, a smile can lie,
但是脚上的鞋子总是会说实话
but the shoes always tell the truth.
她穿的是普拉达  说明她品味很好
They were Prada. Means she has good taste.
根本就不是普拉达
They were not Prada.
只有狠狠地踩在你的小弟弟上
You wouldn't know Prada
你才会知道它是一双普拉达
if one stepped on your scrotum.
好吧  它们很好看  尖尖的
Okay. Well, they were nice. Pointy.
正是  它们非常时髦  但穿起来很疼
Exactly. They were stylish, and very painful to wear.
只有一个肤浅
Only an incredibly shallow,
没安全感的的女人才会宁可成天忍受痛苦
insecure woman would rather be in pain all day long
也不要穿样子一般但舒舒服服的鞋子
than wear a decent-looking, comfortable shoe,
我这里最不需要的就是这种女人
and that's exactly the type I don't need around here.
不对  可以忍受这么多痛苦的人
No. Someone who can handle a lot of pain...
正是你需要的
is exactly the type you do need.
打扰了
Excuse me.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我在用超声波检查你的头部
I'm "Ultrasounding" your head.
你的病还在发作
You're still having seizures.
这可以帮助我们找出问题
This should help us figure out what's going on.
蓝色表格交给警卫
Blue form to the security guard.
你对任何人都不会满意的
You're not gonna be happy with anyone.
所以呢  你的建议是
So what, your advice is...
雇个我不满意的然后还要高高兴兴的
hire someone I'm not happy with and be happy?
不  我的建议要中肯得多
No, my advice is much more subtle.
别再这么混球
Stop being an ass.
你总是找出一些微不足道的缺点
You always find some tiny little flaw
拒人们于千里之外
to push people away.
现在是人们了
Oh, now it's people.
我以为我们在谈雇用员工呢
I thought we were talking about fellowship applicants.
这种事儿你有前科
You have a history of this.
当我决定把你推开时
Well, when I do decide to push you away,
我希望有一个小人在你背后踹你一脚
I hope there's a small person kneeling behind you,
让你狠狠地栽个跟头  摔得头破血流
so you fall down and hurt your head.
服下这些  那边有水
Take these. There's water over there.
蓝色表格给警卫
Blue form to the guard.
然后你就可以走了
And you're done.
你有个完美的人选  而你却搅黄了
You had the perfect person and you blew it.
你也看到她的鞋子了
You saw the shoes.
我不是在说她
I'm not talking about her.
你是在说卡梅隆
You're talking about Cameron.
我说的是每一个
I'm talking about every woman
你在意的女人
you've ever given a damn about.
卡梅隆一点都不完美
Cameron is so not perfect.
人无完人
Well, nobody's perfect.
-特蕾莎修女  -死了
- Mother Teresa? - Dead.
安吉丽娜·朱莉
Angelina Jolie?
-没有医学学位  -现在是谁在吹毛求疵
- No medical degree. - Now who's being picky?
你会孤独终老的  豪斯
You're gonna wind up alone, House.
你说对了
You were right.
她的颞叶里有严重的出血
There's a significant bleed in her temporal lobe.
但没有中毒
But no poisons.
对她的血样  尿样和头发都做了毒理检查
Did tox screens on her blood, urine, and hair
全都没有  做了两遍
Nothing. Did them twice.
他有点脱水
He's a little dehydrated.
给他吊一个盐水袋  再给他喝点橙汁
Put him on a saline drip and give him some orange juice.
我需要一个手术室和一个神经外科医生
I need an operating room and a neurosurgeon.
就现在医院的情况  我很想说不
Given the current crisis, I'm tempted to say no,
但是既然你今天对我这么的体贴...
but since you've been so sweet to me today--
我们的小美人鱼颞叶正在出血
Our little mermaid is bleeding into her temporal lobe.
-术前准备最快你要多久  -二十分钟
- How fast can you have her prepped? - Twenty minutes.
我让外科医生十分钟内就位
You'll have a surgeon in the room in ten.
-卡洛尔先生和夫人  -你是豪斯医生吗
- Mr. And Mrs. Carroll? - Are you Dr. House?
-我是福曼医生  -玛丽还好吗
- This is Dr. Foreman. - Is Mary all right?
手术很成功
The operation went well.
颅内压已经降下来了
The intracranial pressure's been relieved,
肿胀也消下去了
and the swelling's already going down.
谢天谢地  到底是怎么回事
Oh, thank God. Well, what happened?
她是在比赛中撞到头还是...
I mean, did she bang her head at a meet, or did she--
不  没有
No, nothing like that.
那为什么她会脑出血  她会好起来吗
Then why is she bleeding? Is she gonna be all right?
对不起  我们现在还不清楚
I'm sorry. We still don't know.
不是中毒  没有肿瘤  也不是骨癌
No toxins, no tumor, no bone cancer.
肾功能衰竭可能引起
Renal failure could cause
皮疹  发热和肌肉疼痛
the rash, fever, and muscle pain.
也许是种遗传性肾功能紊乱
Maybe it's some sort of genetic kidney disorder
没有家族病史
No family history.
也没有发现尿血或尿毒症
And no blood in her urine or uremia.
是目前没有
Not yet.
你想根据可能出现的症状
You want to do a differential
进行鉴别诊断吗
based on symptoms that might happen?
-你有更好的主意吗  -住口
- You got a better idea? - Stop it.
别管那些我们不知道的
Stop looking for things we don't know
把注意力放在已知的事情上
and focus on what we do know.
除了那上面写着的
What do we actually know,
我们明确知道的还有什么
besides what's up there?
快点
Come on.
告诉我你们所知道的有多难
How hard can it be to tell me what you already know?
-她十二岁  -长时间泡在泳池里
- She's 12. - She spends a lot of time in pools
接触到化学物质
exposure to chemicals.
-她经常旅行  -但从没出过国
- She travels a lot. - But never out of the country.
还有呢
What else?
快想
Come on!
我们就把你安排在这儿
We're gonna put you right here.
我们遗漏了什么
We're missing something.
-什么  -我要是知道  就不会遗漏了
- What? - Well, if I knew that, it wouldn't be missing.
可能她是领养的
Maybe she's adopted
我们看到的不是她的家族史
and we've got the wrong history.
不会  她的眼睛像母亲
No. She's got her mom's eyes
一头的红发和父亲一模一样
and a red patch of hair just like Dad.
会不会是过敏反应
What about an allergic reaction?
这样皮疹和肌肉疼痛都解释得通
That could explain the rash and muscle pain,
但解释不了出血和失神发作
but probably not the bleeding or seizures.
好多的气球
That's a lot of balloons.
你觉得她对聚酯过敏吗
You think she's allergic to polyester?
除非她这么些年都是裸体上场比赛的
Not unless she's been competing in the nude all these years.
那你是怎么想的  这些气球说明什么问题
Then what are you thinking? What do the balloons mean?
要是我们所认为的皮疹
What if the rash
不是皮疹呢
isn't a rash?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
气球谁送的
Who gave her the balloons?
她队里的几个女孩子
Some of the girls from her team.
她们经常来看她
They've been visiting her pretty regularly,
-但没有一个生病  -男孩儿们呢
- but none of them are sick. - What about the guys?
也没有一个生病
None of them are sick either.
具体哪些男孩来看过她
Which guys visited her?
实际上  没有
Actually, none.
她可爱迷人
She's cute. She's nice.
还是个出色的跳水选手
She's a kick-ass diver.
男孩子们为了接近她
You'd think the guys would be falling
会争得你死我活
all over themselves to get close to her.
她才十二岁
She's 12.
她队里最小的男孩也已经十六了
The youngest guy on her team is 16.
那好  也许他们只是对她不感兴趣
Okay, so maybe they're just not interested,
-或者  -他们在躲着她
- or - They're avoiding her.
她的血涂片上有细胞碎片吗
There any cell fragments in her blood smears?
没有  红细胞都完好无损
No. Red blood cells were intact.
再查一遍
Check 'em again.
现在看上去像是从搅拌机里出来的一样
Blood looks like it's been put through the blender now.
-你检查完了没  -你是对的
- You done yet? - You were right.
皮疹不是皮疹
The rash wasn't a rash.
她的皮肤里在出血  是紫癜
She's bleeding into her skin. It's purpura.
血栓性血小板减少性紫癜
Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura?
T打头  你就差那么点儿
Starts with "T". You were so close.
什么会引发这个
What could have set it off?
她的血培养里没有大肠杆菌
She had no traces of E. Coli in her cultures.
显然她还没到更年期
She's obviously not menopausal,
所以不是雌激素的原因
so no estrogen.
还有另外一种可能
There is one other possible cause.
哦  上帝啊
Oh, God.
怀孕时
Pregnancy causes...
女人身体内部发生生化反应
all kinds of chemical and biological changes... in a woman's body--
或者一个女孩的身体  具体情况不同
or a girl's body, as the case may be.
在极为罕见的情况下
In extremely rare cases,
所有东西会像发疯一样
everything goes haywire.
这叫作T.T.P
It's called T.T.P.
血液开始大量凝结
Blood starts clotting like crazy
阻塞大脑和肾脏的血管
and clogs the vessels in your brain and kidneys.
红细胞穿过凝血块时
Red blood cells end up getting shredded
挤得粉身碎骨
as they squeeze past the clot,
就像一个胖子在酒吧里挤来挤去
like a fat guy in a crowded bar.
你肯定知道那是什么样
I'm sure you know what that's like.
我是说  你才十二岁
I mean, you're only 12,
但你已经长大成人了  对吗
but you're all grown up, right?
自己一个人出门  在酒店房间待着
Travel on your own, hang out in hotel rooms...
和队友们一起叫客房服务
getting room service with your teammates.
可能有人偷偷带进几瓶啤酒
Maybe someone sneaks in a couple of beers.
你们开始玩儿转瓶游戏[转瓶选择接吻对象]
You start playing spin the bottle.
接下来你发现自己醒来
Next thing you know you're waking up
全身上下只剩双袜子
with nothing on but your socks.
-不是那样的  -当然不是
- It wasn't like that. - Of course not.
-是你想要的  -是的 是我要的
- You wanted it. - Yeah. I did.
结果没想到他是个混蛋  可是...
He turned out to be a jerk, but--
根据新泽西州法律  准确称呼应该是重罪犯
Actually, under New Jersey law, the term is felon.
我知道自己在做什么
I knew what I was doing.
我们要采用一种叫血浆除去法的治疗方法
We're gonna have to do something called plasmapheresis.
清除你血液里的抗体
Cleans the antibodies from your blood.
我们还要终止你的妊娠
We're also gonna have to terminate the pregnancy.
你们要告诉我的父母吗
You gonna tell my parents?
总要有人去说  石头剪刀布
Someone should. Rock, paper, scissors?
他们不需要知道
They don't need to know.
我会没事的
I'll be all right.
当然你会
Of course you will.
我想如果你已经成熟到有月经的话
I mean, if you're old enough to bleed out of your vagina,
很明显你已经成熟到可以
then obviously you're mature enough...
处理像不依靠父母
to handle a simple thing
一个人完成堕胎手术这样一桩简单的事情
like an abortion without Mommy and Daddy's help.
你会告诉我父母吗
You gonna tell my parents?
根据新泽西州法律  你说了算
Under New Jersey law, you're the boss.
你的女儿得的是T.T.P
Your daughter has T.T.P.
别担心  可以治好的  她会没事的
Don't worry. It's curable. She'll be fine.
等等  T.T.P是什么意思
Well, wait. I mean, what does T.T.P. Stand for?
一个你从来没听说过的复杂词汇
Some really big words that you've never heard before...
等治疗结束  你以后也再不会听到
and, when we're done, will never hear again.
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
那么  我们什么时候能带她回家
Well, when can we take her home?
过几天就可以了
Uh, in a few days.
她需要个小手术
She needs some minor surgery
消除潜在的致病因素
to remove the underlying cause...
然后我们才能给她做...
before we can do the...
另一个很复杂的词汇
another really big word.
潜在的致病因素是什么
What's the underlying cause?
她的下腹部出现一个不正常的发育
She has an abnormal growth in her abdomen.
那是什么样的手术
What kind of surgery?
非常简单
It's-- It's very simple.
我们这儿经常做的
We do it here all the time.
-能再说得详细点儿吗  -老实说  不行
- Could you be a little more specific? - Actually, no.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们快完成了
We're almost done.
坚持坚持
Hang in there.
你现在情况不错
You're doing good.
感觉好吗
Feeling okay?
-嗯  -应该如此
- Yeah. - You should be.
你的血小板计数已经上升了
Your platelets count's up.
脖子感觉怎么样
How's your neck?
看上去挺好  还有什么可以为你做的吗
Looks good. Anything else we can get you?
没有了  谢谢
No, thanks.
好的
Okay.
有件事
Yeah.
我可以见我的父母吗
Can I see my mom and dad?
治疗起效果了  她会好转的
Plasmapheresis is working. She's gonna be fine.
我知道
I know.
-你好啊  -这个我来
- Hi. - I've got these.
能有机会与你见面
I can't even tell you how much I appreciate...
我感激不尽
the opportunity to meet with you.
当我听说你这里有个职位空缺  我就...
The moment I heard you had another fellowship opening, I--
没有空缺
There is no opening.
豪斯
House.
-你必须雇个人  -我知道
- You have to hire someone. - I know.
这个位置已经有人了
Position's been filled.
那我为什么要为一个已经有人的位置
Why am I interviewing for a position
而进行面试
that's already been filled?
说得没错
Exactly.
我今早打电话确认过面试
I called to confirm the interview this morning.
你是不是觉着你这么继续争下去
You figure if you keep arguing,
我会服了你  承认我在骗你然后雇你
I'm gonna cave, admit it's all a lie and hire you?
要不要开停车费免缴证明
Do you need your parking validated?
我不想再面试任何人了
I don't wanna interview anyone else.
你在面试
You're interviewing?
我以为你会叫他们只要
I thought you'd just have them
在简历里放张大头照一起寄过来就行了
send a head shot along with their C.V.
那样不错  我也因此需要你在我身边
That's good, and why I need you around--
约束我不做出格的事
to keep me in my place.
我不能回去  我对你说过了
I can't come back. I told you that.
-没在听  -是嘛
- Wasn't listening. - Right.
你想要我多听听你的话吗  我可以做到的
You want me to listen to you more? I can do that.
是吗
Right.
我已经接受另一个工作了
I already accepted a position somewhere else.
-跟谁  -杰斐逊医疗中心的尤埃尔
- With who? - Yeuell-- at Jefferson.
-回掉它  -为什么
- Unaccept it. - Why?
因为尤埃尔很无聊
Because Yeuell is boring.
他迂腐  啰嗦
He's pedantic and preachy.
还是个小矮人
Because he's short.
因为我希望你回来
Because I want you to come back.
还不足以打动我
Not good enough.
想要涨工资  汽车津贴
Want more money? A car allowance?
还是更好的停车位
Better parking space?
晚餐
Dinner.
而且不是一般两个同事之间的一顿饭
And not just a meal between two colleagues.
是一次约会
A date.
如果我跟你约会
You'll come back to work...
你就会回来工作
if I go out on a date with you?
是的
Yes.
好啊
Okay.
成交
It's a deal.
明天早上见
See you tomorrow morning.
别迟到了
Don't be late.
不会的
I won't.